booktrib.com 2011-12-21

# BookTrib | Privacy Policy »

Effective Date: February, 10, 2011

BookTrib, LLC (“BookTrib,” “we,” or “us”) knows that you care how information about you is used and shared.  This Privacy Policy explains what information of yours will be collected by BookTrib when you use the BookTrib Service, how the information will be used, and how you can control the collection, correction and/or deletion of information.   We will not use or share your information with anyone except as described in this Privacy Policy.  This Privacy Policy does not apply to information we collect by other means (including offline) or from other sources.  Capitalized terms that are not defined in this Privacy Policy have the meaning given them in our Terms of Use http://booktrib.com/about/terms/ .

**Information We Collect**

**User-Provided Information:** You provide us information about yourself, such as your name and e-mail address, if you register for a Member account with the Service [(including by “following,” “liking,” adding the BookTrib application, linking your account to the BookTrib service, etc., on a third party website or network)].  If you correspond with us by email, we may retain the content of your email messages, your email address and our responses.  We may also retain any messages you send through the Service.  You may provide us information in User Content you post to the Service.

**Cookies Information:** When you visit the Service, we may send one or more cookies – a small text file containing a string of alphanumeric characters – to your computer that uniquely identifies your browser and lets BookTrib help you log in faster and enhance your navigation through the site.  A cookie may also convey information about how you browse the Service to us.  A cookie does not collect personal information about you.  A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive after you close your browser. Persistent cookies may be used by your browser on subsequent visits to the site. Persistent cookies can be removed by following your web browser’s directions. A session cookie is temporary and disappears after you close your browser. You can reset your web browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, some features of the Service may not function properly if the ability to accept cookies is disabled.

**Log File Information:** Log file information is automatically reported by your browser each time you access a web page.  When you use the Service, our servers automatically record certain log file information. These server logs may include information such as your web request, Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, browser type, referring / exit pages and URLs, number of clicks and how you interact with links on the Service, domain names, landing pages, pages viewed, and other such information.

**Clear Gifs Information:** When you use the Service, we may employ clear gifs (also known as web beacons) which are used to track the online usage patterns of our users anonymously.  In addition, we may also use clear gifs in HTML-based emails sent to our users to track which emails are opened by recipients.  The information is used to enable more accurate reporting, improve the effectiveness of our marketing, and make BookTrib better for our users.

**How We Use Your Information**

We use the personal information you submit to operate, maintain, and provide to you the features and functionality of the Service.

By providing BookTrib your email address [(including by “following,” “liking,” adding the BookTrib application, linking your account to the BookTrib service, etc., on a third party website or network)], you consent to our using the email address to send you Service-related notices, including any notices required by law, in lieu of communication by postal mail.  [You also agree that we may send you notifications of activity on the Service to the email address you give us, in accordance with any applicable privacy settings.]  We may use your email address to send you other messages, such as newsletters, changes to features of the Service, or special offers.  If you do not want to receive such email messages, you may opt out or change your preferences in your personal Profile. Opting out may prevent you from receiving email messages regarding updates, improvements, or offers.  You may not opt out of Service-related e-mails.

Following termination or deactivation of your Member account, BookTrib may retain your profile information and User Content for a commercially reasonable time for backup, archival, or audit purposes.  Furthermore, BookTrib may retain and continue to use indefinitely all information (including User Content) contained in your communications to other Users or posted to public or semi-public areas of the Service after termination or deactivation of your Member account.

BookTrib may use certain information about you and/or your User Content internally for purposes such as analyzing how the Service is used, diagnosing service or technical problems, maintaining security, and personalizing content.

BookTrib reserves the right, but has no obligation, to monitor the User Content you post on the Service. We reserve the right to remove any such information or material for any reason or no reason, including without limitation if in our sole opinion such information or material violates, or may violate, any applicable law or our Terms of Use Agreement, or to protect or defend our rights or property or those of any third party.  BookTrib also reserves the right to remove information upon the request of any third party.

We use cookies, clear gifs, and log file information to: (a) remember information so that you will not have to re-enter it during your visit or the next time you visit the site; (b) provide custom, personalized content and information; (c) monitor the effectiveness of our Service; (d) monitor aggregate metrics such as total number of visitors, traffic, and demographic patterns; (e) diagnose or fix technology problems reported by our Users or engineers that are associated with certain IP addresses; (f) help you efficiently access your information after you sign in; and (h) track User Content and Users to the extent necessary to comply as a service provider with the Digital Millennium Copyright Act.

**How We Share Your Information**

**Personally Identifiable Information:** BookTrib will not rent or sell your personally identifiable information to others.  BookTrib may share your personally identifiable information with third parties for the purpose of providing the Service to you.  If we do this, such third parties’ use of your information will be bound by this Privacy Policy.  We may store personal information in locations outside the direct control of BookTrib (for instance, on servers or databases co-located with hosting providers).

As we develop our business, we may buy or sell assets or business offerings. Customer, email, and visitor information is generally one of the transferred business assets in these types of transactions. We may also transfer or assign such information in the course of corporate divestitures, mergers, or dissolution.

Any personal information or content that you voluntarily disclose for posting to the Service, such as User Content, becomes available to the public, as controlled by any applicable privacy settings.  To change your privacy settings on the Service, go to your Profile page and edit your profile setting.  If you remove information that you posted to the Service, copies may remain viewable in cached and archived pages of the Service, or if other Users have copied or saved that information.

From time to time, we may run giveaways, contests, special offers, or other events or activities (“Events”) on the Service together with a third party partner.  If you provide information to such third parties, you give them permission to use it for the purpose of that Event and any other use that you approve. We cannot control third parties’ use of your information. If you do not want your information to be collected by or shared with a third party, you can choose not to participate in these Events.

Except as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy, BookTrib will not disclose personal information to any third party unless required to do so by law or subpoena or if we believe that such action is necessary to (a) conform to the law, comply with legal process served on us or our affiliates, or investigate, prevent, or take action regarding suspected or actual illegal activities; (b) to enforce our Terms of Use http://booktrib.com/about/terms/, take precautions against liability, to investigate and defend ourselves against any third-party claims or allegations, to assist government enforcement agencies, or to protect the security or integrity of our site; and (c) to exercise or protect the rights, property, or personal safety of BookTrib, our Users or others.

**Non-Personally Identifiable Information:** We may share non-personally identifiable information (such as anonymous usage data, referring/exit pages and URLs, platform types, number of clicks, etc.) with interested third parties to help them understand the usage patterns for certain BookTrib services.

BookTrib may allow third-party ad servers or ad networks to serve advertisements on the Service. These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to send, directly to your browser, the advertisements and links that appear on BookTrib. They automatically receive your IP address when this happens. They may also use other technologies (such as cookies, JavaScript, or web beacons) to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and to personalize the advertising content.  BookTrib does not provide any personally identifiable information to these third-party ad servers or ad networks without your consent. However, please note that if an advertiser asks BookTrib to show an advertisement to a certain audience and you respond to that advertisement, the advertiser or ad server may conclude that you fit the description of the audience they are trying to reach. The BookTrib Privacy Policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, third-party advertisers.  Please consult the respective privacy policies of such advertisers for more information.

**How We Protect Your Information**

BookTrib uses commercially reasonable physical, managerial, and technical safeguards to preserve the integrity and security of your personal information and implement your privacy settings.  BookTrib cares about the integrity and security of your personal information. We cannot, however, ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to BookTrib or guarantee that your information on the Service may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach of any of our physical, technical, or managerial safeguards.

To protect your privacy and security, we take reasonable steps (such as requesting a unique password) to verify your identity before granting you access to your account. You are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your unique password and account information, and for controlling access to your email communications from BookTrib, at all times.

**Compromise of Personal Information**

In the event that personal information is compromised as a result of a breach of security, BookTrib will promptly notify those persons whose personal information has been compromised, in accordance with the notification procedures set forth in this Privacy Policy, or as otherwise required by applicable law.

**Your Choices About Your Information**

You may, of course, decline to submit personally identifiable information through the Service, in which case BookTrib may not be able to provide certain services to you. You may update or correct your account information and email preferences at any time by logging in to your account and going to your personal Profile and personal Setting for Notifications.   You can review and correct the information about you that BookTrib keeps on file by contacting us directly at Booktrib@BookTrib.com.

**Children’s Privacy**

Protecting the privacy of young children is especially important.  For that reason, BookTrib does not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from anyone under the age of 13 or knowingly allow such persons to register as Members. If you are under 13, please do not send any information about yourself to us, including your name, address, telephone number, or email address. No one under age 13 is allowed to provide any personal information to or on BookTrib. In the event that we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under age 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us at privacy@BookTrib.com.

**Links to Other Web Sites**

We are not responsible for the practices employed by websites linked to or from the Service, nor the information or content contained therein.  Please remember that when you use a link to go from the Service to another website, our Privacy Policy is no longer in effect. Your browsing and interaction on any other website, including those that have a link on our website, is subject to that website’s own rules and policies. Please read over those rules and policies before proceeding.

**Notification Procedures**

It is our policy to provide notifications, whether such notifications are required by law or are for marketing or other business related purposes, to you via email notice, written or hard copy notice, or through conspicuous posting of such notice on the Service, as determined by BookTrib in its sole discretion. We reserve the right to determine the form and means of providing notifications to you, provided that you may opt out of certain means of notification as described in this Privacy Policy.

**Changes to Our Privacy Policy**

If we change our privacy policies and procedures, we will post those changes on the Service to keep you aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances we may disclose it.  Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page.

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this website, please contact us at privacy@BookTrib.com, or send mail to:

BookTrib 155 Post Road East – Ste 8 Westport, Ct 06880
